<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vertcoin</title>
    <link>https://vertcoin.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vertcoin</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 01:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://vertcoin.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Donate</title>
      <link>https://vertcoin.org/donate/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 01:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vertcoin.org/donate/</guid>
      <description>Since Vertcoin did not have an ICO (Initial Coin Offering) or pre-mine (allocation of currency at the launch of the network), the development team relies on community donations for their funding. Whilst the developers work as volunteers and do not get paid a salary, they do make costs to advance the project. On this page, we have detailed a number of donation goals that require additional funds. You may select the goal that mosts suits you; we pledge to use the funding on the designated goal and account for these in our monthly development update.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bitcoin vs Vertcoin</title>
      <link>https://vertcoin.org/bitcoin-vs-vertcoin/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 01:30:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vertcoin.org/bitcoin-vs-vertcoin/</guid>
      <description>Vertcoin had its first block back in Jan 2014. It was built using Bitcoin as a base. Credits to the Bitcoin Core developers who develop the Bitcoin Core software. Vertcoin was created as a GPU mined version of Bitcoin. This enables greater spread of security long term compared to ASICs. If enough devices mine the network, Vertcoin represents a viable alternative to the Bitcoin ASIC mined security model. Ethereum currently uses a mining algorithm similar to the proposed Verthash mining algorithm and achieves security near that of Bitcoin, which means the task is achieveable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community</title>
      <link>https://vertcoin.org/community/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 01:30:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vertcoin.org/community/</guid>
      <description>a { color: #a5a6a7; }    Vertcoin Talk    Twitter    Discord    r/Vertcoin    r/VertcoinMining    Github    Wikipedia    Medium    Vertcoin Statistics    Insight Explorer   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Download</title>
      <link>https://vertcoin.org/download-miner/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 01:30:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vertcoin.org/download-miner/</guid>
      <description> One-Click Miner Download the One-Click Miner v1.2.3(Windows)  &amp;copy;2014-2019 The Vertcoin Core developers  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Download</title>
      <link>https://vertcoin.org/download-wallet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 01:30:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vertcoin.org/download-wallet/</guid>
      <description> Vertcoin Wallet Download the Vertcoin Wallet v14.0 (Windows) (Mac) (Linux)  &amp;copy;2009-2019 The Bitcoin Core developers  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Started</title>
      <link>https://vertcoin.org/get-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 01:30:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vertcoin.org/get-started/</guid>
      <description>.container { text-align: center; }  1: Inform yourself Vertcoin is different than what you know and use every day. Before you start using Vertcoin, there are a few things that you need to know in order to use it securely and avoid common pitfalls.
2 : Choose your wallet Free Vertcoin wallets are available for all major operating systems and devices to serve a variety of your needs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mining Setup</title>
      <link>https://vertcoin.org/mining-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 01:30:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vertcoin.org/mining-setup/</guid>
      <description>p img { max-width: 440px; margin-bottom: 28px; } .content-container img { width: 100%; max-width: 440px; }  Download the One-Click Miner v1.2.3(Windows) Download the Vertcoin Wallet v14.0 (Windows) (Mac) (Linux) Install it Click next 
Click &amp;ldquo;Find P2Pool Nodes&amp;rdquo; 
Enter your wallet address 
If it says waiting for share or online you&amp;rsquo;re done! 
Not working, need help? Head over to Vertcoin Discord. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Specifications</title>
      <link>https://vertcoin.org/specs-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 01:30:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vertcoin.org/specs-explained/</guid>
      <description>.content-container { display: flex; justify-content: space-between; max-width: 1124px; } img { max-width: 53px; }  Built on Bitcoin, receiving any future Bitcoin updates upon specification release confirmation. Vertcoin was the first coin to lock in and activate SegWit. It was activated May 7, 2017  Has the same block time (2.5 mins) as Litecoin and same supply of coins (84,000,000 coins). These changes are well within scaling limits of blockchain growth and orphan generation (1:30)  Mining algorithm proposed is similar to Ethereum&#39;s Ethash (Verthash), meaning GPUs mine competitively.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>